welcome to this darktable tutorial
欢迎使用本《暗表教程》
series darktable is a great program for
系列暗桌是一个很棒的程序
managing and editing your photos
管理和编辑您的照片
including your raw photos if you're a
包括你的原始照片 如果你是
photographer this is a must-have program
摄影师：这是一个必备项目
darktable is very similar to Adobe
Darktable与Adobe非常相似
Lightroom just as professional just as
Lightroom就像专业的
powerful only not just as expensive
功能强大 但不是那么昂贵
because darktable is 100% free and open
因为暗桌是100%免费和开放的
source if you don't already have
来源(如果您还没有
darktable you can download it for free
暗桌你可以免费下载
for windows linux and mac check out my
对于Windows Linux和Mac 请查看我的
other videos where i show how to do that
我演示如何做到这一点的其他视频
but in this video we're going to be
但在这段视频中 我们将成为
exploring the interface of darktable
探索暗台的界面
and we're going to be bringing in some
我们将会带来一些
pictures and showing you just what it
图片 向你展示它到底是什么
can do and how to get started with the
可以做什么以及如何开始使用
very basics so to bring in a picture the
非常基本的 所以带上一张照片
easiest way is to find it on your
最简单的方法是在您的
computer so we can go to like pictures
这样我们就可以去喜欢图片了
here we can find a picture and we can
在这里我们可以找到一张照片 我们可以
just drag and drop that picture in and
只需将该图片拖放到
then we see it appears here we're in the
然后我们看到它出现在这里 我们在
luck the light table right now we can
幸运的是 现在我们可以坐在轻桌上
drag in a few different pictures just
拖入几张不同的图片
like this and every time we drag it in
就像这样 每次我们把它拖进来
you notice a file is being created for
您注意到正在为以下对象创建文件
that picture so as we drag it in we'll
所以当我们把它拖进去的时候 我们会
drag in this one here and then a file
将此文件拖入此处 然后拖入一个文件
gets create to the side of it this is an
在它的一侧创建这是一个
XMP file created by darktable this has
由Darktable创建的XMP文件
all the information about the picture
关于这张照片的所有信息
all the changes that we've made
我们所做的所有改变
which means our picture never gets
这意味着我们的照片永远不会
changed this picture that we that we
改变了这张我们认为我们
bring in will never be edited or
引入将永远不会被编辑或
modified or changed at all directly
直接修改或更改
instead all the changes are kept in a
相反 所有更改都保存在
record next to that picture and then
记录在那张照片旁边 然后
when we go to export the picture it
当我们去出口图片的时候呢
applies those changes so this is sort of
应用这些更改 因此这是一种
similar you can think of the the light
类似的 你可以想到光
table as like a traditional light table
桌子就像一张传统的轻桌
for a photographer that's working with
对于一位正在与
film you bring in the different pictures
拍摄你带来的不同画面
that you want to work with you look at
你想和你一起工作的人看着
them on the light table then you take
把它们放在桌子上 然后你拿着
them into the darkroom to edit them and
把它们放进暗室进行编辑
apply some changes but when you develop
应用一些更改 但当您开发
your final picture you still always keep
你的最后一张照片 你仍然一直保存着
your original negative intact unchanged
你原来的底片原封不动
and the changes are only applied to the
并且更改仅应用于
new picture you've created this will
这将是您创建的新图片
make more sense as we dive in and do
让我们更有意义 因为我们潜水和做
more of this in the future I just wanna
未来会有更多这样的事情发生 我只想
show you another quick way we can bring
向你展示另一种我们可以带来的快速方法
in pictures is in the import tab we can
在图片中 我们可以在导入选项卡中
just click image and import a single
只需点击图像并导入单个
image by itself and go to open
图像本身并转到打开
and just bring in a single image and
只需带来一张图像 然后
then we go to the light table and we
然后我们走到灯光桌前 我们
still see them there we can also bring
仍然可以在那里看到他们 我们也可以带着他们
in the entire folder which is more
在整个文件夹中 哪个更多
practical for most of the time just
大部分时间都很实用 只是
click on under import click on folder
点击导入下的点击文件夹
and then go to the folder that you want
然后转到您想要的文件夹
to bring in and click open and then it
引入并点击打开 然后点击它
brings in every picture in that folder
将该文件夹中的所有图片都带进来
and it also creates on our computer
它还会在我们的计算机上创建
it'll create that XMP file next to each
它将在每个文件旁边创建XMP文件
one of those pictures for us it's just
对我们来说 其中一张照片只是
important that you don't delete this
重要的是 不要删除此内容
it's sometimes when you're first using
有时当你第一次使用的时候
darktable you see this and you think
暗桌 你看到这个 你就会想
that's weird why do I have that so if
太奇怪了 为什么我会有这个 所以如果
you just send if you make an edit to a
如果您对
picture and then just send someone the
照片 然后只需给某人发送
original picture it won't have any of
它不会有任何原创图片
your edits or changes to it just be
您对它的编辑或更改只是
aware of that okay in the light table
在灯光桌上意识到这一点没问题
area we can make changes to the to the
区域中 我们可以将更改为
metadata of the pictures if we hover
如果我们悬停 图片的元数据
over a picture we see these these stars
在一张照片上我们看到了这些星星
appear by default everything has one
显示默认情况下 所有内容都有一个
star a one star rating and when I was
星级为一星级 当我是
first using this I thought well what's
第一次用这个 我想好了 这是什么？
the point why would you give him stars
你为什么要给他星星
like who no one's ever gonna look at the
就像没人会看到的那个人
star rating of the picture but what is
图片的星级 但什么是
used for is to help you organize your
用于帮助您组织您的
pictures if you go out and do a photo
如果你出去拍照片的话会有照片
shoot you're gonna have some pictures
拍吧 你会有一些照片
that aren't that great and you're gonna
不是很棒 而你会
have some that you just really really
有一些你只是真的真的
like so you give them a star rating and
就像这样 你给他们一个星级
then you can come over here at the top
然后你就可以到上面来了
and there's this sort to buy you can
有这样的东西你可以买到
drop a select this drop-down you can say
拖出一个选择此下拉菜单 您可以这样说
sort by rating then all of your
按评级排序 然后将您的所有
five-star pictures will appear appear
五星级图片将会出现
first followed by four stars and three
首先是四星级和三星级
stars all the way down to your one star
一直到你的那一颗星
pictures again one star is sort of the
再说一次 一颗星星是一种
default you can also give the pictures
默认情况下 您还可以给出图片
color tags down here at the bottom if
下面是下面的颜色标签 如果
you just click on one of these colors
你只需点击其中一种颜色
now this has a little red dot on it and
这个上面有一个小红点
so these colors and you can give them
所以这些颜色 你可以给他们
multiple you can give it a red a blue a
多个你可以给它一个红色的 一个蓝色的
purple maybe you find a picture and you
紫色也许你会找到一张照片 然后你
say oh the every picture that has this
说 哦 每一张有这个的照片
person in it I'm going to give it a
里面的人我要给它一个
green tag so you find all the pictures
绿色标签 让你找到所有的图片
that have that person give them a green
让那个人给他们一个绿色的
tag and you can also select multiple at
标记 您还可以选择多个
once in this area so you can click and
在此区域中单击一次 以便您可以单击并
hold down the ctrl key and click
按住Ctrl键并单击
multiple pictures and then you can tag
多张图片 然后你就可以标记
all three of them with that green dot
他们三个都有那个绿点
then when we go to sort by instead of
然后当我们进行排序时 而不是
rating we can sort by color label and it
我们可以根据颜色标签和它进行排序
shows all of our green colors first and
首先显示我们所有的绿色 然后
then followed by other colors as well
然后也跟着其他颜色
and then the non color labeled ones so
然后是非彩色标签的 所以
this is just a way to really manage your
这只是一种真正管理您的
pictures and figure out what's going on
拍下照片 搞清楚是怎么回事
before you bring them into the darkroom
在你把他们带进暗室之前
again if you're just working with one
再说一次 如果你只是在和一个
picture you're not going to want to
想象你不会想要的画面
spend much time in the light table but
花很多时间在灯光桌上 但
if you're working with multiple pictures
如果您正在处理多张图片
particularly like a photo shoot this can
特别是像拍照一样 这个可以
be to a big advantage for you also the
对你也是一个很大的优势
light table area is where we'll export
轻桌区域是我们要出口的地方
our picture when we're done editing so
当我们完成编辑后 我们的照片
we'll have to come back here to do our
我们将不得不回到这里来做我们的
exports let's hop over to the darkroom
出口让我们跳到暗室去
now and take a look at the options there
现在 让我们来看看其中的选项
when we click on darkroom in the top
当我们点击顶部的暗室时
right first of all you can't select
对 首先你不能选择
darkroom unless you have a picture
暗室 除非你有照片
selected so if no pictures are brought
选中此选项后 如果未显示任何图片
in you can't even get into the darkroom
你甚至都进不了暗室
but if you select a picture and it
但如果你选择了一张图片 它
becomes like a little bit lighter gray
变得更浅一点的灰色
then you can click on darkroom and it
然后你可以点击暗室 然后它
will take you into darkroom with that
会把你带进暗室
picture this particular one is a not
想象一下这张图是一张NOT
color which a lot of the feet the tools
哪种颜色是脚上的很多工具
in darktable are going to be color based
在暗表中是基于颜色的
so we can't do much with this one but we
所以我们不能用这个做太多 但我们
can do for example this exposure we can
例如 我们可以进行这种曝光
still adjust the exposure so we'll
仍然调整曝光 这样我们就可以
enable this one and then we can adjust
启用此选项 然后我们可以进行调整
the exposure of this image and we can
这张照片的曝光 我们可以
see we can make it very very exposed or
你看 我们可以让它非常非常暴露 或者
we can make it very underexposed maybe
我们可以让它曝光得很少
we'll just make this one really under
我们要把这件事做得很彻底
exposed and then we'll go to our crop
然后我们就去收割我们的庄稼
and rotate and we can apply a crop so
然后轮换 我们可以应用一种作物
right now it's doing I have it set to an
现在它正在做我已经将它设置为
eight by ten we can do freehand and just
八乘十 我们可以手写 然后
select an area that we want to crop out
选择要裁剪的区域
so we can just zoom in really close to
所以我们可以非常近地放大
like one person and really kind of crop
就像一个人和一种真正的作物
in just how we want or we can come over
就像我们想要的那样 或者我们可以过来
and instead of freehand we can select
而不是徒手 我们可以选择
like this 8 by 10 and we can say we want
像这样8x10 我们可以说我们想要
to 8 by 10 picture and then it will say
到8x10的图片 然后它会说
all right no problem however you scale
好的 不管你有多大规模都没问题
this box it'll always be formatted in an
此框的格式将始终设置为
8 by 10 aspect ratio so we can do it
8 x 10宽高比 这样我们就可以做到
like this and the sides will be cut off
像这样 两边都会被砍掉
here but we just double click and now
但我们现在只需双击
we've kind of cropped this picture we
我们剪下了这张照片
adjusted the exposure a little bit and
稍微调整了一下曝光量
so let's go back to that exposure and
所以让我们回到那个曝光的地方
let's make it very extremely so I want
让我们做得非常好 所以我想
to show you if we make it really really
向你展示如果我们真的真的
overexposed now when we go back into our
现在曝光过度 当我们回到我们的
light table
灯桌
that picture looks different than the
这张照片看起来和
rest of them if we want to export it
剩下的如果我们想出口的话
with this super overexposed we just go
在这种过度曝光的情况下 我们只需
to the export so we select it we go to
到导出 因此我们选择它 然后转到
selected images or no - well it's
选择的图像或没有-好吧 这是
selected we go to export selected and we
选择我们转到导出选择 然后我们
just click the export button and that
只需点击导出按钮 即可
exports that picture as a jpg which is
将该图片导出为jpg格式 这是
what we told it to do quality
我们告诉它要做的事情质量
ninety-five percent we didn't make any
95%的人没有赚到钱
changes to this but now when we go to
对此进行了更改 但现在当我们转到
our computer and we go to that location
我们的电脑和我们去那个地方
where those pictures are we're going to
我们要把那些照片放在哪里
see all those pictures with their
看到所有这些照片和他们的
associated XMP files and a new folder
关联的XMP文件和新文件夹
called darktable
被称为暗桌
exported and this is the picture that we
导出 这是我们的图片
have just modified and processed and
刚刚修改和处理过
exported as a jpg image so that's just a
导出为jpg图像 所以这只是一个
quick run-through let's do one with
快速浏览 让我们来做一个
color just for fun we bring in this one
颜色只是为了好玩我们带来了这一件
with color here and then we can see we
有了这里的颜色 我们就能看到我们
have a lot more we have this brightness
拥有更多 我们拥有这样的光明
and contrast we can adjust these colors
和对比度 我们可以调整这些颜色
and adjust the saturation we can make
并调整我们能做的饱和度
this a black and white photo we can come
这是一张我们可以来的黑白照片
over here there's all kinds of different
在这里有各种各样不同的
options that we're going to look at in
我们将在下面介绍的选项中
the next video but this toggles whether
下一个视频 但这个视频切换是否
it's enabled or our favorites is going
它已启用 否则我们的收藏夹将
to be empty by default right now we
默认情况下是空的 现在我们
click on this color one and these are
点击这个颜色 这些是
kind of some default ones that have a
有点像是默认的 有一个
lot to do with color for example color
与颜色有关的事情很多 例如颜色
correction so we can apply some some
更正 这样我们就可以应用一些
different color to this and give it sort
给它不同的颜色 然后给它排序
of some different you know bring out
一些你知道的不同的东西
sort of the different pixel colors in
中的不同像素颜色
here we can also what do we have here
在这里我们还可以看到我们这里有什么
and there's a lot of different ones if
如果有很多不同的选择
we go to this down here under more
我们在这下面的更多
modules there's all kinds of different
模块有各种各样的不同
ones that we can add in anything we want
我们可以添加任何我们想要的东西
so we can do color zones cover
这样我们就可以做彩色区域封面
reconstruction color mapping there's all
重建颜色映射 这就是一切
kinds of different things and we can
各种不同的东西 我们可以
apply like yet we want to to this so we
就像我们想要的那样 所以我们
enable this one and now we have this
启用这个 现在我们就有了这个
nice sort of vignette that we can adjust
我们可以调整的一种很好的小插曲
the size of it and sort of make this
它的大小和某种程度上使这个
picture a little bit different and again
画面有一点不同 又一次
we go back into light table and we see
我们回到灯光桌上 我们看到
that that is changed so I know I'm
这一点被改变了 所以我知道我是
rushing through a lot of this I'm doing
匆忙地完成了我正在做的很多事情
a kind of a bigger overview but I think
一种更大的概述 但我认为
I'm going to stop this tutorial here
我将在此停止本教程
because in the next video we're gonna
因为在下一个视频中 我们将
spend a lot more time
花更多的时间
in the darkroom going over some of this
在暗室里检查了一些
I just wanted to show you mostly the
我只是想向你展示
light table in this video and how to
在这段视频中的灯表 以及如何
organize and arrange and bring pictures
整理和整理 并带来图片
in to dark table so thanks for watching
在黑暗的桌子上 谢谢收看
I'm sure you have questions at this
我相信你对此有疑问
point but maybe leave your questions or
点 但也许留下你的问题
comments below and then in the next
下面的评论 然后在下一个
video we're going to start solidifying
视频我们将开始固化
some of this information that we've
我们已经发现的一些信息
covered thanks for watching catch you in
覆盖感谢观看抓住你在
the next video
下一个视频